Guide to the Doris Ulmann Photograph Collection ca. 1910-1934 PR 72
New-York Historical Society
- straight, short, thick white hair, parted on side, seated, double breasted suit, tie [Crowninshield, Frank, Editor, Vanity Fair] (Item 2080)
  #2080-2096, 2098 same subject, subject is in "A Portrait Gallery of American Editors", but not this image; mat and mount missing
- straight, short, thick white hair, parted on side, double breasted suit, tie, seated sideways pointing (as if scolding) at a sculpture/figurines two women nude, embracing, a Vanity Fair cover hangs on curtain in background [Crowninshield, Frank, Editor, Vanity Fair] (Item 2081)
- straight, short, thick white hair, parted on side, double breasted suit, tie, standing pointing (as if scolding) at a sculpture/figurines two women nude, embracing, a Vanity Fair cover hangs on curtain in background [Crowninshield, Frank, Editor, Vanity Fair] (Item 2082)
- straight, short, thick white hair, parted on side, double breasted suit, tie, seated, staring into camera [Crowninshield, Frank, Editor, Vanity Fair] (Item 2083)
- straight, short, thick white hair, parted on side, double breasted suit [Crowninshield, Frank, Editor, Vanity Fair] (Item 2084)
- straight, short, thick white hair, parted on side, double breasted suit [Crowninshield, Frank, Editor, Vanity Fair] (Item 2085)
- straight, short, thick white hair, parted on side, double breasted suit [Crowninshield, Frank, Editor, Vanity Fair] (Item 2086)
- straight, short, thick white hair, parted on side, double breasted suit, seated with small open book and pencil [Crowninshield, Frank, Editor, Vanity Fair] (Item 2087)
- straight, short, thick white hair, parted on side, double breasted suit, seated [Crowninshield, Frank, Editor, Vanity Fair] (Item 2088)
- straight, short, thick white hair, parted on side, double breasted suit, seated with papers or manuscripts holding pencil [Crowninshield, Frank, Editor, Vanity Fair] (Item 2089)
- straight, short, thick white hair, parted on side, double breasted suit, seated, arms/hands crossed on lap, legs crossed [Crowninshield, Frank, Editor, Vanity Fair] (Item 2090)
  #2080-2096, 2098 same subject; mat and mount missing
- straight, short, thick white hair, parted on side, double breasted suit, seated at table with small open book [Crowninshield, Frank, Editor, Vanity Fair] (Item 2091)
- straight, short, thick white hair, parted on side, double breasted suit, seated at table with small open book and pencil [Crowninshield, Frank, Editor, Vanity Fair] (Item 2092)
- straight, short, thick white hair, parted on side, double breasted suit, seated staring straight at camera [Crowninshield, Frank, Editor, Vanity Fair] (Item 2093)
- straight, short, thick white hair, parted on side, double breasted suit, seated with small book [Crowninshield, Frank, Editor, Vanity Fair] (Item 2094)
- straight, short, thick white hair, parted on side, double breasted suit, seated staring straight into camera [Crowninshield, Frank, Editor, Vanity Fair] (Item 2095)
- straight, short, thick white hair, parted on side, double breasted suit, seated with pencil and pile of papers or manuscripts [Crowninshield, Frank, Editor, Vanity Fair] (Item 2096)
- balding, medium dark hair, stout, seated, suit, vest, tie, holding magazine, monocle [Shipman, Louis Evan, Editor, Life] (Item 2097)
  #2097, 2163, 3015 same subject; subject is in "A Portrait Gallery of American Editors", but not this image, mat and mount missing
- straight, short, thick white hair, parted on side, double breasted suit, seated with small book [Shipman, Louis Evan, Editor, Life] (Item 2098)
- bald, dark eyebrows, mustache, little beard, jacket, vest, tie, seated with cigar [Cullen, Thomas Stephen, M.B., Professor of Clinical Gynecology] (Item 2099)
- white mustache, bald, military uniform, decorations, seated with book (Item 2100)
  #1326, 1444, 1888, 1889, 1914-1918, 2100-2108 same subject; mat and mount missing
- white mustache, bald, military uniform, decorations, seated with book (Item 2101)
- white mustache, bald, military uniform, decorations, seated (Item 2102)
- white mustache, bald, military uniform, decorations, seated with book (Item 2103)
- white mustache, bald, military uniform, decorations, seated, wearing hat (Item 2104)
- white mustache, bald, military uniform, decorations, seated, wearing hat (Item 2105)
- white mustache, bald, military uniform, decorations, seated, wearing hat (Item 2106)
- white mustache, bald, military uniform, decorations, seated, wearing hat, arms crossed on chest (Item 2107)
- white mustache, bald, military uniform, decorations, seated, wearing hat, hands clasped in lap (Item 2108)
- dark hair, bald, dark eyebrows, not old, gray suit, tie, pince nez eyeglasses, standing in front of cabinet of flat-file-like drawers, anatomical models (?) on top of cabinet of part of human brain? (Item 2109)
  not JHU, not Columbia
- bald, white/white mustache, thick rimmed and thick lenses round eyeglasses, seated, suit, vest, tie [Hendrick, Burton Jesse, Editor, The World's Work] (Item 2110)
  #2110-2113, 2713, 2752, 2929 same subject, subject is in "A Portrait Gallery.. .", but not this image; mat and mount missing
- bald, white/white mustache, thick rimmed and thick lenses round eyeglasses, seated, suit, vest, tie, at desk or table with books [Hendrick, Burton Jesse, Editor, The World's Work] (Item 2111)
- bald, white/white mustache, thick rimmed and thick lenses round eyeglasses, seated, suit, vest, tie, at desk or table with books [Hendrick, Burton Jesse, Editor, The World's Work] (Item 2112)
- bald, white/white mustache, thick rimmed and thick lenses round eyeglasses, seated, suit, vest, tie, at desk or table with books [Hendrick, Burton Jesse, Editor, The World's Work] (Item 2113)
- medium dark straight thin hair, a little disheveled, bags under eyes, deep smile lines, cleft chin, suit, vest, tie, seated [Hapgood, Norman, Editor, Hearst International] (Item 2114)
  #2114-2124, 2996 same subject; subject is in "A Portrait Gallery.. ." but not this image; mat and mount missing
- medium dark straight thin hair, a little disheveled, bags under eyes, deep smile lines, cleft chin, suit, vest, tie, seated [Hapgood, Norman, Editor, Hearst International] (Item 2115)
- medium dark straight thin hair, a little disheveled, bags under eyes, deep smile lines, cleft chin, suit, vest, tie, seated with copy of Hearst International magazine [Hapgood, Norman, Editor, Hearst International] (Item 2116)
- medium dark straight thin hair, a little disheveled, bags under eyes, deep smile lines, cleft chin, suit, vest, tie, chin on hand [Hapgood, Norman, Editor, Hearst International] (Item 2117)
- medium dark straight thin hair, a little disheveled, bags under eyes, deep smile lines, cleft chin, suit, vest, tie, seated [Hapgood, Norman, Editor, Hearst International] (Item 2118)
- medium dark straight thin hair, a little disheveled, bags under eyes, deep smile lines, cleft chin, suit, vest, tie, chin in hand [Hapgood, Norman, Editor, Hearst International] (Item 2119)
- medium dark straight thin hair, a little disheveled, bags under eyes, deep smile lines, cleft chin, suit, vest, tie, seated leaning forward [Hapgood, Norman, Editor, Hearst International] (Item 2120)
- medium dark straight thin hair, a little disheveled, bags under eyes, deep smile lines, cleft chin, suit, vest, tie, seated leaning forward [Hapgood, Norman, Editor, Hearst International] (Item 2121)
- medium dark straight thin hair, a little disheveled, bags under eyes, deep smile lines, cleft chin, suit, vest, tie, seated with Hearst International magazine [Hapgood, Norman, Editor, Hearst International] (Item 2122)
- medium dark straight thin hair, a little disheveled, bags under eyes, deep smile lines, cleft chin, suit, vest, tie, seated with cigarette [Hapgood, Norman, Editor, Hearst International] (Item 2123)
- medium dark straight thin hair, a little disheveled, bags under eyes, deep smile lines, cleft chin, suit, vest, tie, seated with Hearst International magazine, smiling [Hapgood, Norman, Editor, Hearst International] (Item 2124)
- flower in lapel, dark hair, curly, small mustache, with book, at desk [Wright, Richardson Little, Editor, House and Garden, b. 1886] (Item 2125)
  #1073, 1286-1288, 2125-2134, 2999 same subject, subject is in "A Portrait Gallery of Am. Ed.", but not this image, mat and mount missing
- flower in lapel, dark hair, curly, small mustache, with book, at desk [Wright, Richardson Little, Editor, House and Garden, b. 1886] (Item 2126)
- flower in lapel, dark hair, curly, small mustache, at desk with books, papers [Wright, Richardson Little, Editor, House and Garden, b. 1886] (Item 2127)
- flower in lapel, dark hair, curly, small mustache [Wright, Richardson Little, Editor, House and Garden, b. 1886] (Item 2128)
- flower in lapel, dark hair, curly, small mustache, at desk with books, papers [Wright, Richardson Little, Editor, House and Garden, b. 1886] (Item 2129)
- flower in lapel, dark hair, curly, small mustache [Wright, Richardson Little, Editor, House and Garden, b. 1886] (Item 2130)
- flower in lapel, dark hair, curly, small mustache, at desk with books, papers [Wright, Richardson Little, Editor, House and Garden, b. 1886] (Item 2131)
- flower in lapel, dark hair, curly, small mustache, at desk writing [Wright, Richardson Little, Editor, House and Garden, b. 1886] (Item 2132)
- flower in lapel, dark hair, curly, small mustache, seated [Wright, Richardson Little, Editor, House and Garden, b. 1886] (Item 2133)
- flower in lapel, dark hair, curly, small mustache, seated with illustrated book in front of bookshelf [Wright, Richardson Little, Editor, House and Garden, b. 1886] (Item 2134)
- bald, dark round eyeglasses, double breasted jacket [Wells, Thomas B., Editor, Harper's Magazine] (Item 2135)
- bald, dark round eyeglasses, double breasted jacket [Wells, Thomas B., Editor, Harper's Magazine] (Item 2136)
- bald, dark round eyeglasses, double breasted jacket [Wells, Thomas B., Editor, Harper's Magazine] (Item 2137)
- bald, dark round eyeglasses, double breasted jacket [Wells, Thomas B., Editor, Harper's Magazine] (Item 2138)
- bald, dark round eyeglasses, double breasted jacket [Wells, Thomas B., Editor, Harper's Magazine] (Item 2139)
- bald, dark round eyeglasses, double breasted jacket [Wells, Thomas B., Editor, Harper's Magazine] (Item 2140)
- bald, dark round eyeglasses, double breasted jacket [Wells, Thomas B., Editor, Harper's Magazine] (Item 2141)
- bald, dark round eyeglasses, double breasted jacket [Wells, Thomas B., Editor, Harper's Magazine] (Item 2142)
  #1990, 2135-2142, 2746-2751, 2937 same subject, subject is in "A Portrait Gallery.. .", but not this image; mat and mount missing
- young middle age, straight medium dark hair, suit jacket with breast pockets on the outside, vest, tie [Walsh, Richard J., editor, Collier's] (Item 2143)
  #1229-1231, 2143-2152, 2724, 2984 same subject, subject is in "A Portrait Gallery.. ." but not this image
- young middle age, straight medium dark hair, suit jacket with breast pockets on the outside, vest, tie [Walsh, Richard J., editor, Collier's] (Item 2144)
- young middle age, straight medium dark hair, suit jacket with breast pockets on the outside, vest, tie [Walsh, Richard J., editor, Collier's] (Item 2145)
- young middle age, straight medium dark hair, suit jacket with breast pockets on the outside, vest, tie [Walsh, Richard J., editor, Collier's] (Item 2146)
- young middle age, straight medium dark hair, suit jacket with breast pockets on the outside, vest, tie [Walsh, Richard J., editor, Collier's] (Item 2147)
- young middle age, straight medium dark hair, suit jacket with breast pockets on the outside, vest, tie [Walsh, Richard J., editor, Collier's] (Item 2148)
- young middle age, straight medium dark hair, suit jacket with breast pockets on the outside, vest, tie [Walsh, Richard J., editor, Collier's] (Item 2149)
- young middle age, straight medium dark hair, suit jacket with breast pockets on the outside, vest, tie [Walsh, Richard J., editor, Collier's] (Item 2150)
- young middle age, straight medium dark hair, suit jacket with breast pockets on the outside, vest, tie [Walsh, Richard J., editor, Collier's] (Item 2151)
- young middle age, straight medium dark hair, suit jacket with breast pockets on the outside, vest, tie [Walsh, Richard J., editor, Collier's] (Item 2152)
- middle aged, balding, gray mustache, round eyeglasses, somewhat stout, suit, tie, vest [Hendrick, Burton Jesse, Editor, The World's Work] (Item 2153)
  #2153-2159 same subject; subject is in "A Portrait Gallery.. .", but not this image, mat and mount missing
- middle aged, balding, gray mustache, round eyeglasses, somewhat stout, suit, tie, vest [Hendrick, Burton Jesse, Editor, The World's Work] (Item 2154)
- middle aged, balding, gray mustache, round eyeglasses, somewhat stout, suit, tie, vest [Hendrick, Burton Jesse, Editor, The World's Work] (Item 2155)
  #2153-2159 same subject; mat and mount missing
- middle aged, balding, gray mustache, round eyeglasses, somewhat stout, suit, tie, vest [Hendrick, Burton Jesse, Editor, The World's Work] (Item 2156)
- middle aged, balding, gray mustache, round eyeglasses, somewhat stout, suit, tie, vest [Hendrick, Burton Jesse, Editor, The World's Work] (Item 2157)
- middle aged, balding, gray mustache, round eyeglasses, somewhat stout, suit, tie, vest [Hendrick, Burton Jesse, Editor, The World's Work] (Item 2158)
- middle aged, balding, gray mustache, round eyeglasses, somewhat stout, suit, tie, vest [Hendrick, Burton Jesse, Editor, The World's Work] (Item 2159)
- middle aged, balding, medium dark hair, suit, bow tie, vest, seated with pencil, pad, book (Item 2160)
  #2160-2162 same subject, mat and mount missing
- middle aged, balding, medium dark hair, suit, bow tie, vest (Item 2161)
- middle aged, balding, medium dark hair, suit, bow tie, vest (Item 2162)
- balding, medium dark hair, stout, seated, suit, vest, tie, monocle [Shipman, Louis Evan, Editor, Life] (Item 2163)
  #2097, 2163, 3015 same subject; mat and mount missing
- middle aged, receding hair line, medium dark hair, stout, suit, vest, tie, pipe in mouth (Item 2164)
  #2164-2166 same subject, mat and mount missing
- middle aged, receding hair line, medium dark hair, stout, suit, vest, tie (Item 2165)
- middle aged, receding hair line, medium dark hair, stout, suit, vest, tie, pipe in mouth (Item 2166)
- young, thick dark straight unruly hair, seated, suit vest, tie, one hand on table, on hand touching his neck [Mumford, Lewis, American writer and critic] (Item 2167)
  #1182, 2168, 2235 same subject; mat and mount missing
- middle aged, in lab coat, receding hairline, tie, seated at bench with beakers, chin resting on hand [Howland, John, M.D., Professor of Pediatrics, JHU] (Item 2168)
- balding, straight medium dark hair, middle aged, mustache, pince nez eyeglasses, striped suit, tie, in profile, seated at desk with pen writing (Item 2169)
- balding, straight medium dark hair, middle aged, mustache, pince nez eyeglasses, striped suit, tie, 3/4 profile, seated at desk reading newspaper (Item 2170)
- old, white/gray hair, longish beard, mustache, in tuxedo, medals or decorations on jacket, holding a cigarette (Item 2171)
- old, white/gray hair, longish beard, mustache, in leather zipped vest, waterproof canvas jacket, cap, with pipe, looking like a sea captain, actor? (Item 2172)
- young, very thin medium dark hair, balding, mustache, round dark rimmed eyeglasses, suit, vest, tie, seated at desk or table with open book, pen in hand as if signing (Item 2173)
  #2173, 2174, 2202, 2340 same subject; mat and mount missing
- young, very thin medium dark hair, balding, mustache, round dark rimmed eyeglasses, suit, vest, tie, seated slouched in upholstered chair, wavy wallpaper in background (Item 2174)
- middle aged, thinning medium dark colored straight hair, parted in middle, salt and pepper beard and mustache, bags under his eyes [Bridges, Robert, Editor, Scribner's] (Item 2175)
  #2175-2190, 2759, 2995 same subject, subject is in "A Portrait Gallery of American Editors", but not this image, mat and mount missing
- middle aged, thinning medium dark colored straight hair, parted in middle, salt and pepper beard and mustache, bags under his eyes [Bridges, Robert, Editor, Scribner's] (Item 2176)
- middle aged, thinning medium dark colored straight hair, parted in middle, salt and pepper beard and mustache, bags under his eyes [Bridges, Robert, Editor, Scribner's] (Item 2177)
- middle aged, thinning medium dark colored straight hair, parted in middle, salt and pepper beard and mustache, bags under his eyes [Bridges, Robert, Editor, Scribner's] (Item 2178)
- middle aged, thinning medium dark colored straight hair, parted in middle, salt and pepper beard and mustache, bags under his eyes [Bridges, Robert, Editor, Scribner's] (Item 2179)
- middle aged, thinning medium dark colored straight hair, parted in middle, salt and pepper beard and mustache, bags under his eyes [Bridges, Robert, Editor, Scribner's] (Item 2180)
- middle aged, thinning medium dark colored straight hair, parted in middle, salt and pepper beard and mustache, bags under his eyes [Bridges, Robert, Editor, Scribner's] (Item 2181)
- middle aged, thinning medium dark colored straight hair, parted in middle, salt and pepper beard and mustache, bags under his eyes [Bridges, Robert, Editor, Scribner's] (Item 2182)
- middle aged, thinning medium dark colored straight hair, parted in middle, salt and pepper beard and mustache, bags under his eyes [Bridges, Robert, Editor, Scribner's] (Item 2183)
- middle aged, thinning medium dark colored straight hair, parted in middle, salt and pepper beard and mustache, bags under his eyes [Bridges, Robert, Editor, Scribner's] (Item 2184)
- middle aged, thinning medium dark colored straight hair, parted in middle, salt and pepper beard and mustache, bags under his eyes [Bridges, Robert, Editor, Scribner's] (Item 2185)
- middle aged, thinning medium dark colored straight hair, parted in middle, salt and pepper beard and mustache, bags under his eyes [Bridges, Robert, Editor, Scribner's] (Item 2186)
- middle aged, thinning medium dark colored straight hair, parted in middle, salt and pepper beard and mustache, bags under his eyes [Bridges, Robert, Editor, Scribner's] (Item 2187)
- middle aged, thinning medium dark colored straight hair, parted in middle, salt and pepper beard and mustache, bags under his eyes [Bridges, Robert, Editor, Scribner's] (Item 2188)
- middle aged, thinning medium dark colored straight hair, parted in middle, salt and pepper beard and mustache, bags under his eyes [Bridges, Robert, Editor, Scribner's] (Item 2189)
- middle aged, thinning medium dark colored straight hair, parted in middle, salt and pepper beard and mustache, bags under his eyes [Bridges, Robert, Editor, Scribner's] (Item 2190)
- older, thinning medium light hair, parted on left side, mustache, round eyeglasses, striped suit, vest, tie, seated [Finney, John Miller Turpin, M.D., Professor of Clinical Surgery, JHU] (Item 2191)
- middle aged, salt and pepper hair, thinning, dark eyebrows, suit, tie, in profile, with cigarette (Item 2192)
  #1327, 2192, 2215 same subject, mat and mount missing
- middle aged, curly, balding, medium light hair, round eyeglasses, suit, vest, tie, seated in DU's studio chair with turned arms (Item 2193)
  #2193, 2276 same subject, mat and mounts missing
- young, thick dark wavy hair, dark eyes, suit, vest, tie, seated with arms crossed across chest (Item 2194)
  #2194, 2277 same subject, mat and mount missing
- old, balding, medium light or gray hair, deep frown/smile lines, seated with arms resting on back of side chair, suit, tie (Item 2195)
  #2195, 2223, 2296 same subject, mat and mount missing
- middle aged, receding hair line, medium dark hair, suit, vest, tie, seated, cigarette in hand, hand at head (Item 2196)
  #2196, 2200, 2287, 2309, 2319, 2341 same subject; mat and mount missing
- middle aged, white hair, protruding ears, suit, vest, tie, seat in DU's studio chair with turned arms (Item 2197)
  #2197, 2198, 2209, 2242, 2282 man is same subject; mat and mount missing
- middle aged, white hair, protruding ears, suit, vest, tie, seat in DU's studio chair with turned arms (Item 2198)
- short thick curly medium dark hair, white shirt, short sleeved shirt, muscular, young, smiling [Green, Paul Eliot (1894-1981), writer, dramatist] (Item 2199)
- middle aged, receding hair line, medium dark hair, suit, vest, tie, seated, cigarette in hand, hand at head, at desk or table, book on table (Item 2200)
- short thick curly medium dark hair, white shirt, short sleeved shirt, muscular, young, smiling [Green, Paul Eliot (1894-1981), writer, dramatist] (Item 2201)
- young, very thin medium dark hair, balding, mustache, round dark rimmed eyeglasses, suit, vest, tie, seated at table with book (Item 2202)
- white thinning hair, striped suit, vest, tie, watch chain, seated with cigarette or cigar (Item 2203)
- white thinning hair, striped suit, vest, tie, watch chain, seated with cigarette or cigar (Item 2204)
- middle aged, balding medium dark hair, eyebrows, mustache, beard, pince nez eyeglasses, seated in Ulmann's studio chair with turned arms, with cigarette (Item 2205)
  #2205, 2206 same subject, mat and mount missing
- middle aged, balding medium dark hair, eyebrows, mustache, beard, pince nez eyeglasses, 3/4 view, smiling, seated in Ulmann's studio chair with turned arms, with cigarette (Item 2206)
- young, white, or blond salt and pepper thick wavy hair, white artist's smock [Weber, Max, Ulmann's art and design teacher at Clarence H. White School of Photography] (Item 2207)
- striking, dark straight hair, young, dark mustache, striped suit, vest tie, seated in front of drawing [Orozco, Jose Clemente, 1883-1949, Mexican Painter] (Item 2208)
  #2208, 2973 same subject
- middle aged, white hair, protruding ears, suit, vest, tie, seat in DU's studio chair with turned arms (Item 2209)
- bald, some medium dark hair in back, white hair on sides, middle aged, suit, vest, tie, seated in DU's studio chair with turned arms, at table, spools of sewing thread on table, profile view (Item 2210)
  #2210, 2220, 2334, 2320, 2334, 2339 same subject; mat and mount missing
- salt and pepper straight hair, mustache, trim beard, dark eyebrows, middle aged, seated in Ulmann's studio chair with turned arms, with pen at small table, striped suit, vest, tie (Item 2211)
- slightly off-profile view, young, dark hair, round eyeglasses, suit, tie, seated with book on desk [Wood, Frances Carter, Director of Cancer Research] (Item 2212)
  #2212, 2213 same subject; subject is in "XXIV Portraits.. ." Columbia U., but not this image, mat and mount missing
- slightly off-profile view, young, dark hair, round eyeglasses, suit, tie, seated with book on desk [Wood, Frances Carter, Director of Cancer Research] (Item 2213)
- light or white straight hair, middle aged, mustache, double breasted suit, tie, standing, index finger pointing, cover of Vanity Fair pinned to drapery in background [Crowninshield, Frank, Editor, Vanity Fair] (Item 2214)
  #1577-1580, 2214, 2990 same subject; subject is in "A Portrait Gallery.. .", but not this image, mat and mount missing
- middle aged, salt and pepper hair, thinning, dark eyebrows, suit, tie, in profile, with cigarette (Item 2215)
- man, seated at desk or table, pen or pencil in hand, papers, middle aged, very short hair, mustache, suit, vest, tie [Johnson, James Weldon poet, diplomat, songwriter, and anthologist of black culture] (Item 2216)
  #416-419, 1277, 1512, 1513, 1533-1536, 2031, 2069, 2216, 2236, 2237, 2238-2241, 2271, 2977, same subject, mat and mount missing
- seated, middle aged, white hair, parted in middle, mustache, round or oval eyeglasses, book in lap, reading [McClure, Samuel Sidney, Editor, McClure's] (Item 2217)